Three days ago OpenAI pushed a silent update
to their API. No press release. No tweet
storm. Just a changelog entry that most developers
scrolled past.
Every six months we get a new model
and everyone says it changes everything. This time
the benchmark numbers are not the story. The
story is the price drop. GPT-4 level reasoning
now costs ninety-five percent less than it did
in 2023.
I pulled the financials. Klarna replaced seven hundred
customer service agents. Duolingo cut their contractor headcount
by fifty percent. These are not startups —
these are companies with billions in revenue making
hard decisions fast.
The jobs at risk are not the ones
you expect. It is not factory workers. It
is paralegals, junior analysts, content writers, tier-one support.
Basically anyone whose job is to read something
and produce a structured output.
But here is the thing nobody is saying
loudly enough. Every wave of automation creates more
jobs than it destroys — eventually. The question
is whether you are positioned on the creation
side or the destruction side of that curve.
Pick one repetitive task in your workflow. Could
be writing reports, summarising emails, triaging tickets. Automate
it with the API this weekend. Not because
your job is at risk right now. Because
the muscle memory of building with AI is
the actual skill that compounds.